So, I know that in football there are no
two offseasons are the same. It's always
incredible that no roster is ever
exactly the same year to year. So, each
offseason's got to be a little unique.
What about this one presented some
unique opportunities or challenges for
you?
You're right that they are all
different. It's a different puzzle every
year that you got to put together.
We
we feel like we're still the same team
that started off the year
6 and 2, 5 and 1 really. Um 6 and 2 with
the bye week. It was a great bye week.
Um
but we just, you know, had some
unfortunate injuries. Uh you know, a lot
of things led to it. We never want to
use that as an excuse, but
we still have some very good players on
our team. And
you know, we have a start with the
offense with our offensive line
being one of the top ones in the league
when we're healthy.
And the receiver room that we have. Um
Bucky, you know, Baker obviously. That
if we can accentuate that offense, which
I think will be one of the top offenses,
has a chance to be
even a little bit more.
Um and make what's really good even
better.
Um I think that gives us a very good
chance to having some success this year.
But, yet at the same time this year, we
have a lot of pieces on defense that we
need to
um also accentuate and and upgrade or
get some more players. We have a lot of
good players on that side of the ball. A
lot of a lot of young players stepped up
last year. Um some need to step up a
little bit more this year and we're
confident that they will. But, we had an
opportunity to go out and find and look
for what the best players that were
there that fit into what we were doing,
fit into the cap, fit into the puzzle
there. But, it it was regardless of
position. We really had a chance to just
kind of focus on what the best player
was.
As you talk about defense and upgrading
a few positions, I know of course
Lavonte retiring huge impact on not just
the defense, but this organization
overall.
What has he taught you about being a GM?
How has he influenced you and and
influenced the organization as a whole?
We could sit here forever and talk about
Lavonte. Uh
jeez.
He's such a presence just in his own
way. Just
the way he goes about business. I told
him
when I talked to him yesterday that uh
you know, it's just been an honor
to not just be around him the player
because he's I think he's Hall of Fame
going to be in the Hall of Fame at some
point. Um
but, just being around greatness was
awesome. But, it was even more of a
of a
of a great thing to be around him the
person.
And I even told him I said I I want my
kids to grow up to be like you. And
it's, you know, to be the person that
you are. Just selfless, just goes to
work every day.
Uh has a great attitude all the time.
Makes everybody around him better.
Um those are the kind of things that he
brought to our organization and brought
to me. He was a
he was an ear I could I could rely on.
Um I talked to him
you know,
probably more than or deeper than I
would other players just because of the
fact that he's been around so long and
knows so much.
And then of course, you're now having to
say goodbye to your first ever draft
pick that I know holds a special place
in your heart. What is that like for you
personally and then also for you as a
GM?
Yeah, that
that one just, not going to lie, it was
tough.
In the same ways that I talked about
Lavonte, you could echo it with Mike.
Best player we've ever had on offense in
franchise history.
Just a unbelievable person on and off
the field.
He's uh I'm kind of going through the
some of the stages of grief. Um kind of
have
have settled right now on acceptance.
Um
it was, you know,
it was tough, but
we had some great conversations. He's
loves this team. Thinks that we're going
to be a good team. Thinks we're going to
be a great team. Loves his his room.
Loves those receivers. Loves his
quarterback.
But, he was really it was
almost like he was
thinking of his partners there at the
receiver room
and giving them an opportunity now to be
able to step up, which I know they can.
And and have success themselves.
Yeah, and and tell us about how you feel
about that room that we know that Mike
Evans is one of one. But, man to think
about this wide receiver room that he
has left behind. How do you see them
stepping up? Who are the individuals
that you see trying to fill the Mike
Evans shoes if it were? Well, Chris
always steps up. Chris is his his own
entity. And
Chris will now get more opportunities as
well. But, Chris is going to be Chris.
Which is really good.
Um in his role. But, it's going to
probably affect
J Mac
um [snorts]
and Mecca
a little bit more. And
those two have
you know, the ability to
to just really thrive and become not
just good young players, but to become
names in this league.
And then I can't forget about Tez. Um
Tez in in the role that he's going
they're going to carve out for him.
Which will expand. Is going to be
exciting.
And then when it comes to adding new
players, tell me about your philosophy
as a general manager when it comes to
free agency and trades in particular.
And how does that philosophy get
influenced by the particular maybe
positions of need and what that looks
like trying to add positions in free
agency or trades? Well, they've got to
be a good fit for what we're doing.
Um they've got to be a good fit for our
team. We've talked at length here about,
you know, the type of character we look
in players. But,
that is also very important. But, you
know, I do want to stress that that
doesn't mean
that we aren't going to invite some
nasty
mean
aggressive
uh
whatever word you want to throw in
there.
That all is part of being a good
teammate. Uh challenging others.
Bringing a lot of energy.
Um
you know,
it's I think the guys that we that we
signed this year
especially on the defense, kind of
epitomize that. So, we're excited about
that. Yeah, let's let's talk about a few
of those guys particularly on the
defensive side. So, Alex Anzalone,
Alkadeen Muhammad, A Shawn Robinson. And
then of course, if you want to include
special teams ace Miles Killebrew in as
a defensive player. But, uh what do you
see about the things of those individual
guys that excite you and what they could
bring to the defense individually and
then all of them collectively? Alex has
been a player that we've we've faced the
Lions it seems like 100 times in the
last 3 years.
He's always in then of obviously when he
was with the Saints.
He's he's always been
a little bit of a thorn in our side
because of the fact that he's a really
good Well, he's a he's a tough player.
He's sideline to sideline. You know,
he's got all that. But, he's a he's a
really good cover linebacker, which
is very very important in this league
since we're
playing against nickel most more
majority of the time. And you know, it's
been some areas that we've struggled in
the past. And he brings that element,
which which is really
uh going to be uh
it's going to be cool to see. Uh it's
good for us. It's a good asset for us.
Um A Shawn
he's I just remember
you know, the times that we've faced
him.
Especially
going against him when he was in
Carolina.
Uh our offensive line That guy's a to
block. You know, he is he's tough. He's
strong. He's a big big body. He keeps
coming. He's a really good run defender.
Um and keeps after it and gives 100%.
And Miles Killebrew has been
one of the top special teams players in
this league for a while. And Danny Smith
has been
you know, knocking down my door since he
first got here uh talking about what
kind of attitude and what kind of energy
he brings as a captain of a special
teams unit. And how much passion he puts
into his role, which then bleeds into
others. And that's something I'm really
looking forward to.
Yeah, knowing special teams is a unit
that you guys wanted to be able to see
improvement in this year. Looking at the
addition of Killebrew and Danny Smith
and then even re-signing Co. What of
those moves do you feel like really
inspires you and and thinks about, man
this is this is going to make a
difference for our special teams unit?
We'll start with Danny Smith, one of the
better special teams coaches the league
has seen.
Having him and his energy is has been
has been awesome.
And we already talked about Miles and
Co. being a we call middleweight special
teams player.
You know, he he brings it every play.
And he was somebody that jumped off the
tape right away for Coach Smith.
And then um
uh Kenny Gainwell has also been uh a
very good returner, but also a special
teams cover guy that really has a you
know, takes a lot of pride in doing
that. And that's one thing that Danny
Smith brings out in players.
They he gets them excited, which can be
sometimes a mundane
role for some. But, when he's coaching,
they seem to have a lot of excitement
and pride in their job. Which leads me
to think that our special teams are
going to going to be very very good this
year with all those additions. I like
that. And you brought up Kenny Gainwell.
Uh he and then Jake Browning are your
your offensive new additions to the
team. Uh tell me about what made you
bring each of those guys in and and the
thing you're excited about.
Well, with Kenny, he's very good third
down player. He's very good uh runner as
well.
Um he's takes a lot of pride in his
blocking, but he's a excellent receiver.
And the fact that he was
the number two really in in Pittsburgh
or at least started off the season and
they went kind of one A one B
that he was their MVP. It's
you know, that that says a lot about a
player
and for us to be able to get him and
what he's going to add to the dimension
to our offense. He's got a lot of
Bucky
type movement. Um, it's very similar.
I'm not saying that he's replacing Bucky
by any means, but it's you know, it's a
good thing to have along with Sean
Tucker as a bigger back that can power
through arm tackles and and pick up
short yards um with a lot of speed too.
So we've got you know, a three-headed
monster right there right now hopefully
and and uh
we're really really happy. That was
something that we were targeting the
entire time.
And then with um Jake, you know, he's
played a lot of football for a backup um
because of injuries there in Cincinnati.
Thought it was a little bit, you know,
last year they had a lot of injuries as
well. Wasn't quite ideal situation for
him. I think he's a lot better than some
of the tape that he put on or some of
the play that he put on tape last year,
but kind of took a look at his body of
work and you know, he's he's the type of
person that fits that mold of a backup
quarterback because what he can bring
for Baker in that room
um with his you know, the leadership and
then also the experience that he's had.
And then I know not only did you resign
Cove, but also brought back Cade Otton.
Um, I think he's a guy that sometimes is
a little bit unsung for what he
provides. I mean goodness, even just the
number of snaps that guy can play is
crazy. So what really made you guys want
to bring him back and and what are the
things he does for the offense that we
don't always appreciate? Well, first of
all, he's he goes about it the right
way. He's
selfless. He
works his butt off.
And what makes Cade so valuable is
that you know, when you have a tight end
you
you you have some that are just
receivers that F's we call them, some
that are just blockers that are Y's.
Um,
and if you can find a Y which he is, we
consider that also can receive and also
block maybe not at a
elite level at anything, but a really
good level at everything. It makes that
player a very very valuable player. So
especially at that position.
Now of course most importantly, we had
an amazing source on the Cove news. That
would be you.
I love when you break your own news
according to a source, of course. Uh,
tell me what inspired you to first start
doing this years ago and what are some
of your favorite responses you get from
people when you do this?
Well, we always have a
started about three years ago. We
that last Friday of the first week of
free agency kind of slows down and then
you pick things back up on Monday.
And with you know, some of the
some of the second third wave type
players um the following week, but
when we have players that we know we're
going to resign, um
we've already kind of figured out what
the market is. We've kind of come close
to deals with their agents. They're just
they're just waiting for us to call and
and kind of finish it. Um we pick a
player or two while we're out on a boat.
So I have the whole crew
Greenberg, Jackie, Rob McCartney, Mike
Biel, Shane Skannel, Tony Hardy. I mean
we'll have to add to that. Maybe get a
bigger boat next year, but um
we always end up as we're coming back
in. We go out for two or three hours. As
we're coming back into dock, we we
finish it up with doing a signing and
and and Cove just seems like a perfect
boat guy. Who else are you going to sign
on a boat? Yeah, well
We did
Ben Bredeson on a boat couple years ago
on his first contract. So
he's also a boat guy. A boat guy. This
like now it's his own category of
signees where you a boat guy. It's like
it it feels like a special honor.
>> Yeah, sure is. Absolutely.
>> [laughter]
>> That's great. I love it. And and now I
know also as we talk about some of these
offensive guys you've resigned or or new
guys that you've signed, you also of
course now have Zac Robinson as an
offensive coordinator. What do you feel
like he is going to do to help bring out
the best in the guys that you've been
able to put on this roster?
He comes from
a great
mentor
in Sean McVay. And sometimes that gets
overhyped a little bit. Not nothing
taking nothing away from Sean McVay.
He's a great coach.
But just because you work for somebody
doesn't necessarily mean you're going to
do it. But he he has proven um in
Atlanta
that especially when we played against
them that he can get very creative. He
doesn't just bring his offense. He
he he he can modify it depending on what
you have. And
so when we first were going through the
interview process, Todd and I with him,
um he had studied our film. He knew our
players.
Um he gave us a big a plan of what he
could do
um with each and every single one of
them. Um had a plan for Te'o, had a plan
for Jay Mac, had a plan for
Cade if we were able to bring him back.
Had a plan in case Mike left. Um
and it was just a it was very detailed
and it just I think it just brings out
some confidence in players. I know Baker
was as very very excited um with his
short
um amount of time that he had with him
um in LA. I think he felt that Zac was
very responsible for getting him up to
speed quickly in that two-day period
before he or one-day period, whatever it
was before he had to play and win that
game for him. So I know that there's a
lot of confidence.
And then I know that for you we talked
about, you know, free agency, trades,
but the draft, that's your baby. That's
where you love to build a roster. Why is
the draft so important to your strategy
of how you want to build the team?
It becomes very important when you have
a
roster with now our players earn every
penny that they're making, but we have
some players making you know, at the
higher end of the salary scale.
And you know, when you get to that
point, it limits you a little bit in
what you can do in free agency. You have
to look ahead. You have to look at the
future. You have to look at
you want to be able to resign your
really good players
and when their contracts are up, if you
don't do it beforehand.
So you need an influx of young players
that are going to be able to have to
contribute so you can keep the balance
of the team. So I'm not saying we're
moving on from planning on moving on
from anybody, but at all. It's it's just
when you have a a quarterback uh on a
you know, second third contract, when
you've got some you know, other players
and I'm not saying they're limiting what
we can do at all. We're very happy that
we have them. But you need to bring in
young players that can help. So
um we've had a lot of success lately
with the draft. We're signing a lot of
our own players, which is why we're in
that position and that's the goal. So
you want to keep drafting well. That's
the secret to
uh having sustained success. Now I
always love everybody talks about the
draft and oh, taking the best player
available, but we also know that need
does factor in and you want to be able
to take the best player available that
also satisfies one of your needs.
When you look at this year's draft, it
feels like in certain years there's been
themes for you guys of especially things
like speed or special teams or whatever
it may be. Are there themes this year
for what you guys want to accomplish in
the draft and then how well does this
draft match that?
This draft matches with what our needs
are very well. Now that doesn't mean
you're going to
be assured to get one of those players.
It's uh
it can be a little bit a daunting task.
You never know when your players that
you like are going to be taken, but it
does match up well.
But you can never
you can never go wrong if you have to
veer course
um and take another position
that
public or you know, the critics
don't feel you need. At some point
you're going to be happy you got that
player. Uh
showed up last year when we took Imecca.
So I don't think anybody had that on
their bingo card and it it really we're
in a good position right now because of
it.
You know more about this team than
pretty much anybody else. I don't know.
And you care more about this team than
pretty much anybody else in your role. I
wouldn't say that. Tell me as you look
forward to this season,
what excites you? What do you find
yourself just ready for it to be week
one? What are those things that come to
mind for you about this team?
This team is really hungry right now and
the way it
ended last year, I think really lit a
fire under a lot of players.
Um I've had several of them telling me
that they can't wait until OTA's start
to get out there.
And had several of them after the season
ended last year
texting or calling or whatever saying
this is not going to happen next year.
Um I just think I'm excited to see the
the energy and just the uh
just the way they're going to go about
it and attack it this year.
Perfect.